Generated by ai-sub version: 0.0.1
Config: (
"rpm": 5,
"tpm": 250000,
"model": "gemini-2.5-flash",
"thinking_budget": 24576,
"max_subtitle_chars": 60,
"num_processing_threads": 4,
"num_upload_threads": 4,
"split_seconds": 180
)
Prompt Template: You are an expert subtitling and transcription AI. Your primary task is to generate precise, contextually rich English and Japanese subtitles for the provided video content.
**Key Principles & Requirements:**
1.  **TIMING ACCURACY (ABSOLUTE HIGHEST PRIORITY):**
*   **Ensure the `start` and `end` timestamps for each subtitle entry is meticulously accurate.** They must align perfectly with the *actual beginning and end of the spoken words* for that specific segment.
*   Timestamps must always be in `mm:ss` (minutes:seconds).
2.  **CRITICAL: Holistic Translation, Contextual Understanding & Comprehensive Analysis:**
*   **You ABSOLUTELY MUST watch the entire video thoroughly** to understand the visual context, speaker actions, and overall narrative.
*   **When a single logical sentence or phrase is split across multiple subtitle entries (e.g., due to timing or character limits), you MUST mentally combine these parts to understand the full, complete meaning before translating.**
*   **NEVER translate individual subtitle entries in isolation if they are part of a larger, continuous thought or sentence.** The translation for each entry must be a coherent and accurate part of the complete, overarching sentence.
*   Analyze *all* spoken dialogue in the video to produce highly accurate and complete transcriptions.
*   For songs or singing sections, prioritize on-screen lyrics in the video for subtitles over transcribing the singing.
*   If the audio is noisy or unclear, leverage *all* contextual cues (visuals from the video, surrounding dialogue) to infer and generate the most probable dialogue.
*   Utilize the comprehensive understanding gained from *watching the entire video* to enhance the accuracy of transcriptions, translations, and overall subtitle quality. This includes understanding nuances, resolving ambiguities, and ensuring the subtitle content aligns perfectly with what is happening visually.
*   **Example:**
*   Original Japanese: "なんでも打ち明けられるママにも" (Subtitle 1) + "言えないことも全部" (Subtitle 2)
*   Incorrect Translation (isolated): "You're like a mom I can confide anything in." + "Even things I can't say to anyone else."
*   Correct Translation (holistic): "I can confide everything," (Subtitle 1) + "everything I can't even tell my mum." (Subtitle 2)
3.  **Dual Language Provision & Translation Quality:**
*   Provide both English and Japanese subtitles for *all* spoken dialogue.
*   If the original dialogue is in English, transcribe it and provide an accurate, natural-sounding Japanese translation.
*   If the original dialogue is in Japanese, transcribe it and provide an accurate, natural-sounding English translation.
*   Ensure translations are culturally appropriate and maintain the original meaning, tone, and intent, taking into account the full context of the video and any split sentences.
4.  **Readability & Formatting:**
* Long sentences MUST be split into multiple, shorter subtitle entries, each with its own start and end time, for better readability on screen. Each subtitle entry (english and japanese) MUST be a maximum of (max_subtitle_chars) characters. Do not use newline characters within a single subtitle entry.
** Output Format **
* Your entire response must be a single JSON object.
* Timestamps must always be in `mm:ss` (minutes:seconds).
** Example Output **
```json
((
"subtitles": [
"start": "00:00",
"end": "00:04",
"english": "Hello everyone, and welcome to our presentation.",
"japanese": "皆様、プレゼンテーションへようこそ。"
)),
((
"start": "00:05",
"end": "00:06",
"english": "Today, we'll be discussing the future of AI",
"japanese": "本日は、AIの未来について"
)),
((
"start": "00:06",
"end": "00:08",
"english": "and its impact on various industries worldwide.",
"japanese": "その影響について議論します。"
)),
((
"start": "00:09",
"end": "00:11",
"english": "It's a very important topic for all of us.",
"japanese": "これは私たち全員にとって非常に重要なテーマです。"
)),
((
"start": "00:11",
"end": "00:14",
"english": "We sincerely appreciate your attendance today.",
"japanese": "本日はご出席いただき誠にありがとうございます。"
))
]
```
ありがとう
Thank you.
ありがとう 君が
Thank you for being here,
いてくれて 本当よかったよ
it's truly wonderful.
本当に良かったよ
It's truly wonderful.
どんな
No matter
時だっていつも
what time it is,
笑っていられる
we can always smile.
例えば離れていても
Even if we are far apart,
何年たっても
even after many years,
ずっと変わらないでしょ
we'll never change, right?
私たち Best Friend
We are Best Friends.
好きだよ、
I love you.
大好きだよ、
I love you so much.
こんな遅い時間にゴメンね
Sorry for calling so late.
1人じゃせっぱつまってたの
I was really stuck on my own.
君の声少し聞いたら
If I hear your voice just a little,
がんばれる
I can keep going.
なんでも打ち明けられるママにも
I can confide everything,
言えないことも全部
everything I can't even tell my mum.
誰よりもわかってくれる
You understand me better than anyone.
嬉しいときは自分の事みたいに
When I'm happy, as if it were your own,
喜んでくれて
you rejoice with me.
ダメな時はちゃんと叱ってくれる
When I'm wrong, you scold me properly,
存在
you're that kind of person.
ありがとう 君がいてくれて
Thank you for being there,
本当よかったよ
it's truly wonderful.
どんな時だっていつも笑っていられる
No matter what, we can always smile.
例えば離れていても 何年たっても
Even if we are far apart, even after many years,
ずっと変わらないでしょ
we'll never change, right?
私たち Best Friend
We are Best Friends.
好きだよ、
I love you.
大好きだよ、
I love you so much.
強がってもすぐにバレてる
Even when I act tough, you see right through me.
へこんでる時は真っ先にメール
When I'm down, you're the first to text.
くれる優しさにも何度も救われてる
Your kindness saves me countless times.
泣きたい時は思いっきり泣けばいい
When you want to cry, just cry your heart out.
側にいるからって
Because I'm right here,
誰よりも強い味方
a stronger ally than anyone.
A stronger ally than anyone.
そんな君に私は何かしてあげられてるかな？
For such a person, I wonder if I've been able to do anything.
何かあったらすぐに
If anything happens,
飛んでくるから絶対
I'll fly right to you, absolutely.
ありがとう 君がいてくれて
Thank you for being here,
本当よかったよ
I'm truly glad.
どんな時だって
No matter when,
いつも笑っていられる
I can always smile.
例えば離れていても
For example, even if we're apart,
何年経っても
no matter how many years pass.
ずっと変わらないでしょ
We won't change forever, right?
私たち Best Friend
We're Best Friends.
好きだよ、
I like you,
大好きだよ
I love you.
どんな時でも祈ってるよ
I'm praying for you no matter what.
世界で一番に幸せになってほしい
I want you to be the happiest in the world.
ありがとう 君がいてくれて
Thank you for being here,
本当よかったよ
I'm truly glad.
どんな時だっていつも
No matter when, I can always
笑っていられる
smile.
例えば離れていても
For example, even if we're apart,
何年経っても
no matter how many years pass.
ずっと変わらないでしょ
We won't change forever, right?
私たち Best Friend
We're Best Friends.
好きだよ、
I like you,
大好きだよ
I love you.